

# ILYAS KERBAL

# • DETAILS •

Rabat, 111000 Morocco +212 681564731 kerbalsc@gmail.com

#### LINKS

<u>Linkedin</u>

GitHub

**Portfolio** 

**StackOverflow** 

# ° SKILLS °

**Android Development** 

Android SDK

Git

Kotlin

**Android Studio** 

**Automated Testing** 

Test-driven development

Firebase

SQL

Continuous Integration

Agile and Scrum

JIRA

**Automated Testing** 

Python

Java

Google Cloud Platform

Google Play

GitHub

Dagger Hilt

Jetpack Compose

Google Material Design

Google Maps SDK

CI/CD

# PROFILE

Software engineer with **6+ years of experience** in **Android development**. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Data Science from the School of Information Science (ESI). I have worked on numerous **freelance projects** and built and *published many apps* on my own. Self-motivated, flexible, and adaptable; I can adapt to both self-starting and collaborative environments while focusing on **high-quality results** under **strict deadlines**.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Android Engineer at BidSys, Rabat, Morocco

July 2020 — June 2022

- Performing the end-to-end integration and test of software components and deploying them onto hardware through both manual testing and automated test development.
- · Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs.
- Work with the product and design teams to understand end-user requirements and use cases and translate them pragmatic and effective technical solutions.

## Freelance Android Developer at UpWork

August 2016 — May 2022

- Build quality applications based on product requirements.
- Translate designs and wireframes into high-quality code.
- Provide suggestions on UI Design for a superior user experience based on prior experience.
- Ensure the best possible performance, quality, and responsiveness of the application.
- Integrating third-party libraries and APIs
- Building from early stages, shipping through Google Play Store.

## EDUCATION

## Android Kotlin Developer, Android Development, Udacity

February 2022 — May 2022

- Taught by Google Engineers, introducing the latest and best practices for Android development: MVVM architecture, Dependency injection (DI), ViewModel, LiveData, Data Binding, Repository Pattern, Navigation Component, Unit Testing, End-to-End Testing, Jetpack library, and more.
- Worked with more than 19 projects and built 5 on my own.

# Bachelor's degree, School of Information Sciences (ESI), Rabat, Morocco

January 2016 — October 2020

Data engineering and computer science.

# Java Android Development, Treehouse

February 2016 — May 2016

- Solid understanding of the full mobile development life cycle.
- Using built-in sensors to detect motion, orientation, and various environmental conditions
- Designing, building, and maintaining high-performance, reusable, and reliable Java code.

# Math / Physics (MPSI), Ibn Tahir High School, Errachidia, Morocco

January 2014 — December 2016

## Mathematics BAC, SIJILMASSA high school, Errachidia, Morocco

January 2011 — December 2014

#### RELEVANT INTERNSHIPS

## Mobile Developer at LE DIGIMENTAL LIMITED, Casablanca, Morocco

January 2020 — July 2020

- Building and maintaining a Flutter app for hotels' internal management.
- Android UI design principles, patterns, and best practices.

#### COURSES

TOEIC - English

#### **ATTENDED EVENTS**

P DevFest, Google Developer Groups (GDG), Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

December 2019

# **★** RELEVANT PROJECTS

# Who is using my WIfi?

Android (native) app lets users discover and keep track of devices connected to the network. The app received a total of **6+ Million downloads** on Play Store.

https://gitlab.com/ilyasKerbal/wumw

#### PostureWise

Android & IOS app built using Flutter. The app helps fix bad posture by providing short, simple exercises arranged in 30 days program.

https://gitlab.com/ilyasKerbal/posturewise

# **Location Reminder**

TODO list app with location reminders that remind the user to do something when the user is at a specific location.

https://github.com/ilyasKerbal/location-reminders

# Political Preparedness

An application that provides civic data intended to provide educational opportunities to the U.S. electorate using data provided by the Google Civic Information API.

#### Asteroid Radar

Asteroid Radar is an app to view the asteroids detected by NASA that pass near Earth, you can view all the detected asteroids given a period of time with data such as the size, velocity, distance to earth and if they are potentially hazardous